Guide to the Philip G. Zimbardo Papers SC0750
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Audiovisual materials, Series 1
  - Audiorecordings
    - Poet/Psychotic Tape, 8 selections, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 87)
    - Group Debriefing-High Scores MAS, 1985 Mar 6; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 87)
    - Psych 199: Zimbardo-Psych of Police Confessions, J.B. Stockdale-Surviving as a Prisoner-of-War, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 87)
    - Psych 1: Rumor, 2003 Apr 3; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 87)
    - The Psychology Minute: 9-11, 3 segments, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 87)
    - The Todd Mundt Show, 2002 Aug 15; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 87)
    - Todd Mundt Show, NPR-Shyness, 2002 Aug 15; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 87)
    - Richard Clark on The Self Deception of People in Jonestown, 1981; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 87)
    - Moonie Documentary-Radio, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 87)
    - Bias Letters, 1985 Mar 19; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 87)
    - Jim Jones-Father Cares (tape 1 of 2), 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 87)
    - Moonies-Makepeace, Powell, Schwark, Gilles, 1983 May 4; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 87)
    - Father Cares-Jonestown Call in Pgm., KQED-FM, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 87)
    - Peoples Temple Experience, 1 & 2, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 87)
    - Peoples Temple USA (no. 1), 1998 Dec 21; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 87)
    - Peoples Temple Experience, 3 & 4, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 87)
    - Father Cares: Jim Jones (N.P.R.), Tape 1 (sides 1 & 3), 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 87)
    - Father Cares: The Last of Jonestown, Side 3 (tape 2 of 2), 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 87)
    - Jonestown-Day Before, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 87)
    - Moyer-West Coast Feed, Father Cares, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 87)
    - East Coast Feed-NPR, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 87)
    - Hypnotic Jonestown Procedure, 1974 Apr 9; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 87)
    - WPA-Rollo May, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 87)
    - Psychology at Yale through the Decades (no. 1), 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 87)
    - Psychology at Yale through the Decades (no. 2), 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 87)
    - Psychology at Yale through the Decades (no. 3), 1993 Apr 30-May 3; 0 audiocassette(s) (Box 87)
    - Peoples Temple Experience, 5 & 6, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 87)
    - Richard Clark/Diane Louie: Interview with Don Sullivan, Phil Zimbardo, 1979 Feb 11; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 87)
    - Father Cares: Jim Jones (N.P.R.), Tape 2 (side 2), 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 87)
    - Carol Burnett on Shyness, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 87)
    - Father Cares-Jim Jones (tape 2 of 2), 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 87)
    - Psychology 1: Lecture 2, 1979 Oct 2; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 87)
    - Psychology 1: Lecture 3, 1979 Oct 4; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 87)
    - Psychology 1: Lecture 4, 1979 Oct 9; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 87)
    - Psychology 1: Prejudice, 1979 Nov 6; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 87)
    - Psychology 1: Final Lecture, #18, 1979 Nov 29; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 87)
    - The Cult Phenomenon Symposium-Mem. Aud. Stanford, Tape 1, 1979 Nov 19; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 87)
    - The Cult Phenomenon Symposium-Mem. Aud. Stanford, Tape 2, 1979 Nov 19; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 87)
    - The Cult Phenomenon Symposium-Mem. Aud. Stanford, Tape 3, 1979 Nov 19; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 87)
    - Meyer-Brainwashing, Korean POW, 0 audiocassette(s) (Box 87)
    - Psych 199: Mind Control, George Louie, 1983 Apr 20; 0 audiocassette(s) (Box 87)
    - Paul Horn-Taj Mahal/Hypnosis, 0 audiocassette(s) (Box 87)
    - Time Perspectives Interview-Libby Morimoto, Subject 4A, 1993 Feb 28; 0 audiocassette(s) (Box 87)
    - Shyness-Conversation with Carol Burnett, 1977 Jan 13; 0 audiocassette(s) (Box 87)
    - Hypnotizability, Harvard-Form, 1986 Apr 9; 0 audiocassette(s) (Box 87)
    - Madness-Dr. David Rosenhan, 1980 Mar 4; 0 audiocassette(s) (Box 87)
    - Psychology 1: Sex, 1979 Nov 27; 0 audiocassette(s) (Box 87)
    - Psychology 1: Lecture, Time Perspective, 1981 May 14; 0 audiocassette(s) (Box 87)
    - Music & Madness, 1980 Jan 17; 0 audiocassette(s) (Box 87)
    - Psych 158: Madness, Dr. P. French, 1980 Jan 10; 0 audiocassette(s) (Box 87)
    - Psychology 1: Lecture, Shyness, 1977 Jan 20; 0 audiocassette(s) (Box 87)
    - Psychology 1: Lecture, Time Perspective, 1981 May 14; 0 audiocassette(s) (Box 87)
    - Sex Demo, 1988 May 3; 0 audiocassette(s) (Box 87)
    - Madness Group, 1984 Oct 25; 0 audiocassette(s) (Box 87)
    - The Psychology and Drama Interface-Ryan and Zimbardo, Nat. Assoc. of Drama Therapists, 1986 Nov 9; 0 audiocassette(s) (Box 87)
    - WPA-Making Sense of Madness, 1983; 0 audiocassette(s) (Box 87)
    - Rumor Tape-Stanford (original), 1971; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 87)
    - Carlo Prescott, KGO Financial Hour, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 79)
    - Time Perspective Interview Jay-Son Low, 1993 Mar 8; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 79)
    - Mrs. J. Elliott/At Stanford Boystown & Psych 1 Class, 1976 Feb; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 79)
    - Zimbardo-Madness Lecture WPA, 1983; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 79)
    - Psychology 1, 1977 Jan 18; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 79)
    - APA-99th Annual Convention: The Joys of Being a Psychologist, 1991 Aug 16-20; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 79)
    - APA-99th Annual Convention: "Video in the Classroom: Enhancing Teaching or Replacing Teachers?", 1991 Aug 16-20; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 79)
    - Psychology I: Introduction, 1979 Sep 26; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 79)
    - Cult Phenomenon Symposium, 1979 Nov 19; 3 audiocassette(s) (Box 79)
    - Perspectives on Madness; Pat Ryan Madness in Literature, 1979-1980; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 79)
    - The Psychology Today series: interviews and sessions from the 80th Annual APA meeting, Hawaii, 1972. Tape B-31 Prison Reform, by Phillip G. Zimbardo, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 140)
    - Madness, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 140)
    - [Allan] Funt interview, 1984 Nov 19; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 140)
    - Psychology 158: Perspectives on Madness. Pat Ryan., 1980 Jan 24; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 140)
    - Kevin Bierks. Julia Bryson (11/10). Thea Marston (11/10). Sara Piestrup., 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 140)
    - Shy puppet study. Bing [nursery school], 1980 Summer; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 140)
    - Rumor: coherent story., 1999 Jan 8; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 140)
    - Phil Zimbardo: Strategies of Prevention, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 140)
    - Father Cares: the last of Jonestown. National Public Radio., 1981; 2 audiocassette(s) (Box 140)
    - Stanford prison. American Psychological Association 104th annual convention, Toronto., 1996 Aug; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 140)
    - The Lucifer Effect: understanding how good people turn evil. Read by Kevin Foley., 22 optical disc(s) (cd) (Box 140)
    - Naples. Evil., 2005 May 9; 1 optical disc(s) (cd) (Box 140)
    - Public Safety Starts in Jail. Morgan Moss/Penny Patton. "Living Successfully" with host Bob Keeton. Radio program for April 2004 before Southside Jail Program started., 2004 Apr 5; 1 optical disc(s) (cd) (Box 140)
    - Carlo Piccione-Comments on the Madness Model, 1980 Aug; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 140)
    - People 004, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 140)
    - Jonestown. Last Hour., 1978 Nov; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 140)
    - NPR. Jonestown call-in segment. Gary Scott: torture., 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 140)
    - Torture. KQED., 2000 Oct 23; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 140)
    - Evil in the world and terror in our nation: transferring vulnerabilities into resilience. American Psychiatric Association, 2002 annual meeting., 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 140)
    - Side A: NYU seminar tape. Side B: Poet & Psychotic tape., 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 140)
    - WIZ-Meet wiz/out of here/you all got it., 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 140)
    - The WIZ. APA original., 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 140)
    - Jim Jones Last Hour speech-Peoples Temple, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 140)
    - LH to PGZ, 1973 July 23-24; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 140)
    - Psychology 1 Music-openers. Lecture 5., 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 140)
    - Psychology 1 Music lecture 10; lecture 12, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 140)
    - Psychology 1: lecture 1-Handsome teacher/teach me/young girl, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 140)
    - Zimbardo, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 140)
    - George Klein; Kalami Onozco, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 140)
    - Poet/psychotic. 8 selections-repeated., 1955 May 18; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 140)
    - Psychology 1, 1999 Feb 8; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 140)
    - Sexual Intercourse. Human Sexuality demo. Produced by Adam Zimbardo. Written/hosted by Phil Zimbardo., 1988 May 3; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 140)
    - NPR. Chemicals in the workplace., 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 140)
    - Psychology 1: Sex lecture-Intro., 1985 May 9; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 140)
    - NPR. Chemicals in the workplace. Discontinuities & Madness., 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 140)
    - Jim Jones' last hour. W.C. Miller dialogue., 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 140)
    - Psychology 1: Music. Lectures 1-5. Rumor: Mixed story., 1999 Jan 8; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 140)
    - Shyness, etc. Philip Zimbardo, J. Bines, G. Greenbe, 1999 May 30; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 140)
    - Psychology 1: #2, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 140)
    - Jim Jones' last hour speech. Peoples Temple., 1978 Nov 18; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 140)
    - Social Influences Processes class [Psych] 135, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 140)
    - Stanford Prison Experiment Background/study. Applications. Ross class., 1984 May 30; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 140)
    - Phil Zimbardo Hypnosis Induction. Harvard scale. Psychology 1. April 11th., 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 140)
    - The Wiz. APA 8/02. Copy for APA show., 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 140)
    - Vulgar and the Woodcutter-demo tape, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 140)
    - NYU-seminar tape (Side A); Poet & Psychotic tape (Side B), 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 140)
    - Rumor Transmission demo, 2000 Jan 7; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 140)
    - Tape II Max McCauley; Claire Silverman, 1980 Nov 11; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 140)
    - EEG Discontinuity-Amnesia cond. Zimbardo, Butler, Laberge, 1990 May 19; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 140)
    - APA Mentor tradition, Mentor symposia, 1987; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 140)
    - APA Symposium WGBH, 9/2, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 140)
    - Zimbardo on marketing (ideas for P & L); Adam Zimbardo: Diary of a fugitive & interview, 1974 May; 1972 Nov 7; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 140)
    - TEMPO: interviews Seidman/Z., 1973 Nov 5; 2 audiocassette(s) (Box 140)
    - Zimbardo/Maslach PT interview, 2000 May 18; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 140)
- Born-digital materials, Series 2
  This series consists of born-digital material created by Dr. Zimbardo, as well as websites created by and about him.
  - Computer media
    This series consists of Dr. Zimbardo's born-digital material, which was stored on floppy diskettes and optical discs.
    Access to Collection
    This series is still in process.
    - Miscellaneous computer media (optical) (Box 177, Box 159)
    - Miscellaneous computer media (magnetic) (Box 178, Box 160)
  - Websites, Series 9
    The materials consist of Dr. Zimbardo's personal website, and other related websites, captured by University Archives staff.
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    The websites were captured using HTTrack, a free offline browser utility. HTTrack downloads a website from the Internet to a local directory, building recursively all directories, getting HTML, images, and other files from the server to your computer. HTTrack arranges the original site's relative link-structure allowing you to open a page of the mirrored website in your browser, browse the site from link to link.
    - http://www.zimbardo.com/, 60.3 megabyte(s) (109 files in 5 directories)
      Captured July 27, 2011 via WinHTTrack.
      Personal website of Philip G. Zimbardo, including biographical information, teaching and lecture information, and links to media and resources.
    - http://www.prisonexp.org/, 1999-2011; 29.4 megabyte(s) (933 files in 28 directories)
      Launched first in December 1999, this website features a slide show and information about this classic psychology experiment, including parallels with the abuse of prisoners at Abu Ghraib (2006).
    - http://www.socialpsychology.org/retire/, 2003; 1.95 megabyte(s) (104 files in 4 directories)
      Website designed by the Social Psychology Network, one of the largest Internet sites devoted to psychological research and teaching, to honor the 2003 retirement of Philip G. Zimbardo, former president of the American Psychological Association and one of the great names in social psychology. Included are excerpts from more than 750 tributes, sent from more than 25 countries.
    - http://heroicimagination.org/, 2015
    - http://www.thetimeparadox.com/, 2015
- Professional files, Series 3
  This series is arranged into several subseries, including: academic files; awards/grants; biographical; correspondence; court cases; lectures/symposia/conferences; miscellaneous; photographs; professional organizations (APA); professional organizations (other than APA); speeches/eulogies by Zimbardo; and television and film.
  Materials in this series consist of documents and photographs collected and compiled throughout Zimbardo's professional life.
  The APA subseries highlights Zimbardo's significant involvement with the American Psychological Association, including his presidency in 2002. Included are conference materials and documents related to the Presidential Task Force on External Funding (a panel which urged a curb on influence of corporations, particularly pharmaceutical companies, on the profession of psychology).
  Awards includes honorary degrees, awards Zimbardo received from professional organizations, from Stanford University, and from others. Grants include applications and awards from NSF, NIH, NIMH, ONR, and others.
  The biographical subseries includes CVs, interviews with Zimbardo, clippings, and various other publicity about Zimbardo.
  Correspondence consists primarily of incoming letters from the 1990s up until 2004.
  Lectures/symposia/conferences includes printed materials from events as well as text of some speeches given at these events.
  Television and film consists of documentation relating to Zimbardo's involvement with the Candid Camera and Discovering Psychology series. Also included are documents relating to other television programs and films that Zimbardo participated in or consulted on.
  Court cases includes files maintained by Zimbardo for research and also those in which he was called in for testimony.
  Academic files include some of Zimbardo's student work from his days at Brooklyn College and Yale.
  Photographs include images of Zimbardo with students, and images he used for presentations or publications.
  - Academic files
    - Experience and Undergraduate Perception, Brooklyn College, 1954 (Box 151, Folder 30)
    - Perception, (Major Area Paper), 1957 (Box 151, Folder 31)
    - Comparison of the Formal and Informal Structure of a Retail and an Industrial Enterprise, 1952 (Box 151, Folder 32)
    - Involvement and Communication Discrepancy as Determinants of Opinion Change, (Dissertation), 1959 (Box 151, Folder 33)
  - Awards/grants
    - Sagan Award, 2002 Dec (Box 101, Folder 35)
    - AAAS Award Recommendation Materials to Pamela Willenz, APA, 2001 (Box 101, Folder 36)
    - APF Awards and Grant Applications, 2000 (Box 101, Folder 37)
    - ASSU Teaching Award, 2001 (Box 101, Folder 38)
    - Robert S. Daniel Award, 1999 (Box 101, Folder 39)
    - Hilgard Award, 1999 (Box 101, Folder 40)
    - Honorary Ph.D., Univ. of Thessaloniki, Greece, 1998 Mar (Box 101, Folder 41)
    - Bing Award Letters, 1993 (Box 101, Folder 42)
    - IG Nobel Award, 2003 (Box 101, Folder 43)
    - Gores Award (1 of 2), 1989 (Box 101, Folder 45)
    - Gores Award (2 of 2), 1989 (Box 101, Folder 46)
    - Gores Award, 1989 (Box 101, Folder 47)
    - Lucidity Institute Grant 1EQA676-$10,000, 1999 (Box 101, Folder 48)
    - Ethics in Society Grant-$7,500 for Teaching Ethics in Class, 2004 (Box 101, Folder 49)
    - Czech Award-VISION 97 Prize, 1997 (Box 102, Folder 13)
    - APF Award: Nomination Criteria Materials, 2000 (Box 102, Folder 66)
    - APF Award: Nomination Criteria Materials, 2000 (Box 102, Folder 67)
    - APF Award: Applications, 1999-2000 (Box 102, Folder 68)
    - APF Award Application Materials: Teaching Methods/Practice, 2000 (Box 102, Folder 69)
    - APF Award Application Materials: Administrative Facilitation, 2000 (Box 102, Folder 70)
    - APF Award Application Materials: Instructor Resources, 2000 (Box 102, Folder 71)
    - Dean's Award: Teaching, 2000 (Box 102, Folder 72)
    - APF Award Application Materials: Recommendations, 2000 (Box 102, Folder 73)
    - APF Award Application Materials: Influence, 2000 (Box 102, Folder 74)
    - APF Award Application Materials: Influence on Minority Students, 2000 (Box 102, Folder 75)
    - APF Award Application Materials: Teaching Methods, 2000 (Box 102, Folder 76)
    - APF Award Application Materials: Teacher Training, 2000 (Box 102, Folder 77)
    - APF Award Application Materials: Curricula/Courses, 2000 (Box 102, Folder 78)
    - APF Award Application Materials: Research-Teaching, 2000 (Box 102, Folder 79)
    - APF Award Application Materials: Classroom Performance, 2000 (Box 102, Folder 80)
    - Dinkelspiel Award, 1980 (Box 157, Folder 1)
    - Gores Award application, 1975 (Box 157, Folder 2)
    - APF teaching awards: letters (Box 157, Folder 3)
    - Special letters (commendations of P.Z.'s work) (Box 157, Folder 4)
    - Awards-Nominations (Box 157, Folder 5)
    - American Psychological Association Presidential citation, 1994 (Box 157, Folder 6)
    - Bing Fellow Award, 1994-1997 (Box 157, Folder 7)
    - APF Contributions to Education in Psychology Award (Box 157, Folder 8)
    - Cox research 1995 for 1996 (Box 157, Folder 9)
    - Film Festival awards (Box 157, Folder 10)
    - National Media Award, 1973 (Box 157, Folder 11)
    - California State Psych. Assoc. Award for Distinguished Scientific Achievement in Psychology, 1978 (Box 157, Folder 12)
    - Awards for Discovering Psychology videos (Box 157, Folder 13)
    - Phoenix Award, 1984 (Box 157, Folder 14)
    - NYU Favorite Professor of the Class of 1965 Silver Anniversary Award, 1990 Jun (Box 157, Folder 15)
    - Gores Award, 1990 (Box 157, Folder 16)
    - STC International Audiovisual Competition-Award of Excellence, 1991 (Box 157, Folder 17)
    - WPA Outstanding Teaching Award (Box 157, Folder 18)
    - Originals of letters in Gores Award book, 1989 (Box 157, Folder 19)
    - Awards - Misc. (Box 157, Folder 20)
    - APF Teaching Award (Box 157, Folder 21)
    - APF Gold Medal Award (Box 157, Folder 22)
    - Awards-Misc. (Box 157, Folder 23)
    - DeLeon Award (Box 157, Folder 24)
    - Service award/honors (Box 157, Folder 25)
    - Rutgers honor, 2005 May 20 (Box 157, Folder 26)
    - Awards-Misc. (Box 157, Folder 27)
    - Society for Teaching of Psychology Award, 1999 (Box 157, Folder 28)
    - Virtual Nobel Prize in Psychology, 2004 (Box 157, Folder 29)
    - Rutgers Degree, 2009 May 20 (Box 157, Folder 30)
    - AAAS Award, 2003 (Box 157, Folder 31)
    - AAAS (Box 157, Folder 32)
    - Sagan Award, 2002 (Box 157, Folder 33)
    - NSF grant proposal, 1986 Jan 10 (Box 150, Folder 1)
    - Initial statement submitted to ONR-Group Effectiveness, 1977 May 1 (Box 150, Folder 2)
    - ONR reports (Box 150, Folder 3)
    - ONR annual TR-Z-S-01. Assessment of the utility of an automated message system to influence participation rates among problem-solving teams., 1979 Jan (Box 150, Folder 4)
    - OTL proposal, 1994 (Box 150, Folder 5)
    - NIMH grant proposal: Social Cognitive Dynamics in Psychopathology-submitted, 1986 Jan 24 (Box 150, Folder 6)
    - NIMH grant proposal w/o budget and w/o appendices (2), 1986 Jan 24 (Box 150, Folder 7)
    - NIMH grant proposal: abstract page, research plan, letters from consultants, references, 1986 Jan 24 (Box 150, Folder 8)
    - NIH "...time perspective biases", 1991 (Box 150, Folder 9)
    - Grants-Misc. (1 of 3) (Box 150, Folder 10)
    - Grants-Misc. (2 of 3) (Box 150, Folder 11)
    - Grants-Misc. (3 of 3) (Box 150, Folder 12)
    - Current research [ONR proposal], 1979-1980 (Box 150, Folder 13)
    - ONR archival notebook (Box 150, Folder 14)
    - List of graduate students in NIH Social Training Program (copy given to AGZ by Altman) and Personality Training Program, 1972-1978 (Box 150, Folder 15)
    - Grants: Social Training grant (proposal) with corrections, 1986 Sep 9 (Box 150, Folder 16)
    - Grant, Social Training (field and lab), 1979-1984 (Box 150, Folder 17)
    - Miscellaneous student projects (Box 150, Folder 18)
    - Impact of viewing JFK-Butler research (Box 150, Folder 19)
    - The Time of Homeless People-Elissa Epel, 1989 Dec (Box 150, Folder 20)
    - "Perception of Unexpected Events", 1989 Nov (Box 150, Folder 21)
    - Human SS review: assessment of reaction to anomalous events, 1989 Nov (Box 150, Folder 22)
    - SP Office protocol: EEG correlates of cognitive decisions. S. LaBerge, 1987 Jan (Box 150, Folder 23)
    - Sponsored Projects protocol: Psychophysiology of anomalous events., 1986 Oct (Box 150, Folder 24)
    - New Hypnosis proposal to Sponsored Projects Office, 1985 Mar 11 (Box 150, Folder 25)
    - Anomalous Events. Human subjects research-request for review, 1985 Jan (Box 150, Folder 26)
    - Generating explanations for anomalous events, 1977 Feb. (Box 150, Folder 27)
    - [Ruth] Polak research, 1992 May (Box 150, Folder 28)
    - IRB (Zim) (Box 150, Folder 29)
    - "Case report" drafts (Box 150, Folder 30)
    - IRB Stanford (Box 150, Folder 31)
    - G. Bower IRB proposal (Box 150, Folder 32)
    - Post-experimental questionnaire. Retest subjects (Box 150, Folder 33)
    - Craig Haney [dissertation and other papers] (Box 150, Folder 34)
    - NSF grant-materials (extra) (Box 150, Folder 35)
    - NSF grant-budget (Box 150, Folder 36)
    - Analysis of Dyadic Discontinuity Disclosure, 1982 Jul (Box 150, Folder 37)
    - Contents and Forms of Self-Awareness (Box 150, Folder 38)
  - Biographical
    - Vitae-Non Current (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Autobiography-Zimbardo, 2003 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Biographical, 2000-2001 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Zimbardo-Bio (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Bios, Non-Current (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Zimbardo Press & Bio Info (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Research Interests (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Vita-PGZ, 1989 (Box 102, Folder 27)
    - Vita: PGZ Newspaper articles-Boston Globe (glossies of article with negatives), 1983 Jul 22 (Box 102, Folder 28)
    - Maslach CV (Box 109, Folder 16)
    - Psychology Today "PZ, Emperor of the Edge", 2000 Sept/Oct (Box 158, Folder 1)
    - North American Journal of Psychology Interview with PGZ, 1999 Jun (Box 158)
    - Zimbardo's research domains (Box 158)
    - Dr. Philip Zimbardo-clippings (Box 158)
    - Random House author questionnaire (biographical) (Box 158)
    - Zim-Vitae (Box 158)
    - Vita, 2002 (Box 158)
    - Sabbatical (Box 158)
    - PGZ-Website (Box 158)
    - Edge interview SPE Abu Ghraib, 2005 Jan 16 (Box 158)
    - Recollections of a Social Psychologist's Career: an interview wth Dr. Philip Zimbardo (Box 158)
    - Articles about Zimbardo (1 of 4) (Box 158)
    - Articles about Zimbardo (2 of 4) (Box 158)
    - Articles about Zimbardo (3 of 4) (Box 158)
    - Articles about Zimbardo (4 of 4) (Box 158)
    - Psychology Trading Cards-Zimbardo (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Retirement party, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Publicity
      - C.C.N.Y.-N.Y.U. Harlem Summer Project, 1965 (Box 17, Folder 8)
      - Press-Prejudice (Box 17, Folder 9)
      - Press-Prison Experiment (Box 17, Folder 10)
      - Prison Incarceration "3 Strikes Initiative" (Box 17, Folder 11)
      - Psychology (Box 17, Folder 12)
      - Press-Rape (Box 17, Folder 13)
      - Sex, Sexuality, Sexism, Women (Box 17, Folder 14)
      - Press-Shyness (Box 17, Folder 15)